<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>ourmachine.net</title>
        <link>https://ourmachine.net</link>
        <description></description>
        <generator>Zola</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="https://ourmachine.net/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>Memory I</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>https://ourmachine.net/writing/memory-i/</link>
                <guid>https://ourmachine.net/writing/memory-i/</guid>
                <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The last word is with the philosopher who maintains against Aristotle that the earth moves because it is alive.”&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Frances Yates, &lt;em&gt;The Art of Memory&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; (1966)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Europe, politicians claim the novel coronavirus poses the greatest challenge to its nations since World War II. I look up different descriptions of World War II, which try to subsume many names and conflicts like the Winter War, the Phony War, the Second Thirty Year War, the Second Sino-Japanese War, and the Great Patriotic War.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder why I have not heard of the 1918 influenza pandemic prior to this year, and I look up why it’s called the Spanish flu.  Spain was one of the few countries in the region to remain neutral during the preceding First World War. As the story goes, Allied and Central forces suppressed the news of a deadly pandemic to maintain morale. Being under a lesser state of censorship, Spain became the media epicenter of the contagion and remains foremost in the memory of the pandemic today.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;divider&quot;&gt;&amp;#9675;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent one of my more anxious mornings in early March reading about a niche yet controversial disagreement in 1584 about memory.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term memory palace refers to a technique of memorization in which you use the imagination of a structure to store a memory. For example, you could memorize a long poem, which you recount by imaginally walking through a long hallway you remember from your childhood. In each door of the hallway, you place an object that will help you remember the next verse in the poem. The objects may be figural statues or more abstract, psychedelic associations. Cicero popularized the memory palace concept in De Oratore, in which he recounts the poet Simonides’ grace to escape a collapsed building and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;artofmemory.com&#x2F;blog&#x2F;simonides-of-ceos-81.html&quot;&gt;elucidate the technique&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It became popular amongst oratory education in Rome and subsequent traditions, but encountered a challenge to its method in the sixteenth century called Ramism. Based on the work of a scholar Petrus Ramus, Ramism emphasized a form of memorization with a “dialectical” method, in which knowledge was organized through tree charts on the printed page. Whereas memory palaces emphasized associational linkages, in Ramism objects of knowledge took on a serial relation to each other within a broader taxonomic framework of disciplinary knowledge, similar to the animal kingdom charts common in introductory biology today. By contrast in memory palaces, the image representing a memory does not need to belong to its narrative domain: an old path down a mountain may embody a character’s exit from a story that takes place only within a flat wasteland.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1584, an English advocate of Ramism denounced Giordano Bruno’s texts on memory palaces that emphasized the aestheticized, associational, and imaginal realm. Bruno, a friar, philosopher, mathematician, poet, cosmological theorist, and occultist, would be burned at the stake over a decade later in 1600. In his surviving texts on memory palaces, as described by academic Frances Yates, he emphasizes:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Images [in memory palaces] must be charged with affects, and particularly with the affect of Love, for so they have the power to penetrate to the core of both the inner and outer worlds — [which is] an extraordinarily mingling here of classical memory advice on using emotionally charged images, combined with a magician’s use of an emotionally charged imagination… which have power to open ‘the black diamond doors’ within the psyche.”&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1&quot;&gt;1&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The eroticism running throughout Bruno’s art of memory was unfavorable to puritanical English regimes at the time, and the “asceptic” dialectical method of the Ramists appeared a favorable means to make memorizing the beautiful and abject in epic poetry more sterile to a student. As Ramism came to be a very influential tool for Puritanical theologians, the culture war enacted through polemics on memory also revolved around more subtle forms of esotericism present in Bruno’s art related to the invocation of astral imagery. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;De Umbris Idearum (On the Shadows of Ideas)&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; is Bruno’s earliest work devoted to the art of memory. In the text, he lists thirty sets of descriptive images, which include images of the zodiac, planets, lunar mansions, and horoscope houses among others. Each set of these images is meant to be placed within a corresponding segment of a circle, divided equally by thirty spokes to form a wheel. In one segment of the wheel, both scholars and gods, like Hipparchus the astronomer and Endimion the Olympian shepherd, become associated with the course of the moon and  “the leftward movement of the sphere of fixed stars.”&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#2&quot;&gt;2&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; In another segment, we encounter Saturn, associated with a man on a dragon accompanied by an owl. While imaginally walking through the wheel structure, what emerges is a memory palace devoted not only to memorization of cosmological movement but also of narrative cosmological archetypes. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;memory_seal_zodiac.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bruno&#x27;s Memory Seal based on the zodiac&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Giordano Bruno, Memory seal (1582)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bruno’s many descriptions of astral memory palaces, however, were not purely his creation, but evidence of a larger tradition that today we encapsulate under the term Hermeticism, which itself built on traditions of Islamic astronomy and astrology. Embracing the phrase “as above, so below,” the Hermetic tradition cultivated techniques for an individual to connect an inner cosmos reflecting the outer,  opening the psyche’s “black diamond doors” of which Bruno wrote. The technique of inhabiting astral memory palaces architected an imaginal cosmos as a tool for self-transformation, what might even be referred to today as self-improvement, to reorient the individual toward the planetary. Cosmology in the Hermetic sense, however, was not a static knowledge artefact but conceived of as fundamentally alive. Therefore, the construction of an inner cosmos was not unidirectional, but cybernetically took place in dialogue with a living world. Rather than apophenia, it sought a kind of mutual autopoiesis. Like today’s therapeutic practices of eye movement therapy or somatic releasing, this astral meditative practice acknowledged close attention to memory as an important practice of self-transformation, but as one that fundamentally and firstly conceived of the individual in relation to the planetary scale. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;memory_BR_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Blade Runner 2049&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blade Runner 2049&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the zeitgeist of the planetary scale, I’ve been struck recently by feeling a deep inadequacy of the corners of contemporary media philosophy I’m acquainted with to offer a useful lens on the present. You would think a cultural discipline based on design critique would be the first to the insightful forefront when the digital divide becomes stark and parts of civilization’s lives become online, fully “on air.” The quarantined memory maker—part human, replicant, and believed impossibility—from &lt;em&gt;Blade Runner 2049&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; shows the speculative gap in our current tools to virtually communicate the memorable, and the problematized design space of quarantine jargon does little by way of reclaiming this stable base from which to work. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;memory_diagram.png&quot; alt=&quot;Lines of Flight diagram&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think a key task in the coming years is the struggle to redraw many maps on horizontal, vertical, and inner planes, and this means for us, here, reading this, to institutionally interrogate where boundaries of accepted knowledge are allowed to resettle. Without narrative externalities—like star stories and inhuman artefacts as tools for resilient memory practices—priced into our approach toward resilient ecosystems, we will end up with the same poverty of thought that can’t see the trees until the forest has been cut down. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is right to turn toward science fiction in an extraplanetary future. It is also equally correct to examine planetary agency in all aesthetic practices, not as a return to simpler causal narratives nor as an ontological salve, but to move toward integration of a richer inner realm of the possible and preexisting. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;memory_clarke.png&quot; alt=&quot;Arthur C. Clarke, Profiles of the future&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Arthur C. Clarke, &lt;em&gt;Profiles of the Future&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; (1962)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A key failure on display for the first half of the year has been the visceral inability to imagine the “impossible.” In response to the UK Labour party’s 2019 proposal to make internet access a public utility, a politician claimed, “Everything is horribly, brutally possible.” While intended to invoke the supposed terror of the price for a prescient, more equal future, something rang correct in the phrase as we now approach the next decade of social unrest, supply chain collapse, and “transhumanist” exit for the global 1%. Everything being horribly, brutally possible feels like the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;thejaymo&#x2F;status&#x2F;1195297198784831489?s=20&quot;&gt;call of the coming years&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and should be kept in mind when reflecting on the events of the last several months. It became apparent that even when faced with the death toll in Wuhan and the new hospitals built in several days to meet demand, many in countries earlier in the infection timeline simply and willfully could not imagine a pandemic would affect them. At a deeper level, they could not imagine that a phenomenon changing basic societal scripts could take place at all. Societal change, it was revealed, had been consigned to the realm of the fanatic and the paranoid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This inability to consider the possible has real and not unprecedented costs. For centuries, many people of color and many at risk have been speaking against governments that are structurally disinterested in allowing parts of the population to live. Existing in denial of risk, it is the societal inability to hear, accept, and truly internalize this possibility that continues to make excuses, in the face of great grief, for the calculated incompetence of governments that are little more than violent, financialized bureaucracies of empire. We already know it will only get worse with the fallout from climate change. However, the extreme 2020 energy of everything being horribly, brutally possible is not a one-sided tool. As Federico Campagna said in a recent seminar, “It is possible to change the metaphysics [of a historical existence] regardless of your standing within society.” Campagna’s work, which often references writers from the Hermetic tradition recounted above, feels more prescient and useful than most of today’s academic work in its world-building attempts. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A popular media theorist and friend recently derided the public’s choice to believe in astrology over astrobiology, coming to the conclusion that humanity’s knowledge must be preserved in distant bunkers and Mars given over to science fiction writers. I wonder, though, how these disciplinary distinctions would hold, were it not for the character of Saturn with a perching owl, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Songline&quot;&gt;songlines&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as navigation, and the psychic voyage to the star Arcturus that keep our heads turned to the story of the cosmos. Constellations have stored stories thousands of years old and continue to be used for wayfinding. Astrology itself may be the oldest and most impactful science fiction ever created. Because astral stories can exist without the epistemological support of telescopes, they are both woefully unreal and extraordinarily resilient narrative technology for institutional memory—perhaps one of the few intergenerational computers we’ve managed to construct so far. As in the ritualized memory palaces of five centuries past and many older, more diverse traditions, occult philosophy across traditions has effectively been thinking at the planetary scale for millennia. It was not invented by today’s narrow definition of computation.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, event horizons have always been multidimensional. The breaking of disciplinary boundaries today is not the overprescription of pattern recognition, somehow seeking mystical order amidst disorienting change. I believe it&#x27;s an ability to think, sit deeply with, and act on the limitations of what you deem possible. In fact, the main form of personal resilience available to us in the present moment is not the ability to predict what will happen, but the calm ability to hold space for everything that could possibly, potentially happen that was formerly outside of your worldview. It’s this ability that means you can use your position for others—to make the masks, sow the seeds, and retell the star maps, &lt;em&gt;despite&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and perhaps even before a toxic change in the air that surrounds you and &lt;em&gt;in service&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; to our strange and interdependent futures—without exception.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1: Frances Yates, &lt;em&gt;The Art of Memory&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; (166): 253.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
2: Ibid, 217.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;BPR.png&quot; alt=&quot;Blogger Peer Review Seal&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Many thanks to the Blogger Peer Review for their thoughts and feedback.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Flies</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>https://ourmachine.net/writing/flies/</link>
                <guid>https://ourmachine.net/writing/flies/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skipping two stones that hit,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
waiting, filing my nails.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hung words to dry&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
over the same long lakeshore,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
I rock it out of them.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Someday&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, my aunt says,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;someday&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, she always had&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
a thing for adverbs,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;this place&#x27;ll be zapped, evap-ed,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
flat like a bug.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her dog chases my stones.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
He waddles, uninterested,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
missing one leg,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
he lost in the war&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but still smiles like tin.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
I return to the emery board.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
while true == 0:&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Keep cycling &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;while I sit, wondering&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
at the raw iron smell&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
seeping from the gut&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
of a simple pond.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He sniffs at my arm.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;An infinite loop&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
is actually very small&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
I tell my aunt.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She doesn&#x27;t ask&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
where it goes,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
but beats at the line,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Still wet. Soon, soon!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Viridian Moment in Time Chosen Arbitrarily</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>https://ourmachine.net/writing/viridian-moment-in-time/</link>
                <guid>https://ourmachine.net/writing/viridian-moment-in-time/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give up the love that didn’t come to you.
It came in around back
where the porch doesn’t screech.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A house is a frame held in minds that lived there.
It gathers thoughts, touches; it moves on.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sand is smooth until it’s not.
The ocean isn’t your mother;
it’s too small for that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>New Time Machines Working Group</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>https://ourmachine.net/writing/new-time-machines/</link>
                <guid>https://ourmachine.net/writing/new-time-machines/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;20200205_ak_diagram.png&quot; alt=&quot;Diagram&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;caption-1&quot;&gt;A schematic representation of the gearing of the Antikythera Mechanism, namely the true sun pointer and pointers for the planets (Freeth and Jones, 2012).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The revival of magical beliefs is possible today because it no longer represents a social threat. [...] Astrology too can be allowed to return, with the certainty that even the most devoted consumer of astral charts will automatically consult their watch before going to work.”&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Silvia Federici, &lt;em&gt;Caliban and the Witch&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to make a case that we live in Millenarian times. The belief in the coming transformation of society often relies on a cataclysmic event, or rather it relies on an event that makes the prior world not only unlikely, but impossible, to inhabit. In the last century, we’ve seen similar narratives come and go, with the continued threat of nuclear annihilation and Y2K’s easy passage. The pathology of the world ending at any instant (1945-) is very different from its slow uninhabitability (1970-). Yet we live in both.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To navigate the weirdness that consumes contemporary life, you might hear someone frame a current event simply as a marker of “this point in the timeline.” For many, the elections of the last half-decade could be underwritten by a simple intermission: this is simply the timeline we’ve been given, and it’s the worst one. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The end of the world often collapses into synonym with the end of time. It signals that we simply can’t imagine a moment that resembles its uninherited and discontinuous moment after. So while the notion of directional time intrinsically suggests its potential end, Millenarian thought assumes its place as simply one expression among many of the medium of time. Key, however, in the distinction between the threat of the end of the world and the end of time, is the differing means and ends that utter their coming. Apocalyptic Millenarianism doesn’t ask individuals to embrace a cosmos, but to commit to a single, unidirectional timeline. The sudden cancellation of the future holds little ground, and its declarations should be met with suspicion—even when they invoke crises that cannot be denied—because they don’t give us worlds.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;divider&quot;&gt;&amp;#9675;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with whispers and clearer annunciations of the end of worlds, we are witnessing a new articulation of the seasons. This has been the warmest, brightest winter I’ve experienced in Berlin yet. While the disappearance of difference will gradually, and then suddenly, lend way to extremes, I&#x27;ll probably never learn to enjoy someone telling me to embrace “Scorpio season.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was eleven, my aunt told me I could choose any books at the Barnes &amp;amp; Noble. Coming away with a Graham Hancock book on Egypt and &lt;em&gt;Astrology for Dummies&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, my timeline became at least partially, faultily fated. Having studied the stars from a young age through a $13.99 book series that includes other classics like &lt;em&gt;Sales Management for Dummies&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;,  I was fascinated by how planets and stars stood &lt;em&gt;in aspect to each other&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. The tyranny of collapsing Hellenic-tradition sun signs into singular adjectives for short seasons and personalities will not satisfy me. Still, astrology can be seen as an art of the quality of time: seasonal tailwinds and shifts in soil chemistry, influencing what can grow. Another way to say this, is that astrology seeks to articulate and &lt;em&gt;actively craft&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; how time’s disposition and affordances are governed, taking the event more than the self as its subject. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In astrological communities, from Vedic to Hellenic practitioners, debates on method and upcoming configurations occupy the core of the conversation. One of these configurations that convey a shift in the quality of time occurred in mid-January. Following roughly 33-year synodic cycles, Saturn conjunct Pluto also coincided with the beginning of WWI and, according to most forums, ushered in neoliberalism at the start of the 80s. Another deeper, it is said, more fundamental shift in the quality of time will occur later this year. Jupiter conjuncts Saturn every 20 years, and for approximately 200 year cycles, Jupiter-Saturn conjoin in signs of the same element, giving us two centuries of Fire, Earth, Air, or Water in turn. Referred to also as triplicity cycles, our current cycle phase initiated in 1802 gave us over two hundred years of Earth, in which we saw global industrialization and extraction, from rare earth minerals to fossil fuels. In December 2020, the Jupiter-Saturn conjunction will take place in the sign of Aquarius and fully initiate the next two centuries of Air.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Astrologers speculate differently on how we’ll meet this predicted change, but it is at least certain that the cycle will continue and recur. Though possessing its own Millenarian currents, astrology is another expression inherent to time—one that precludes its singular end.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;divider&quot;&gt;&amp;#9675;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the increasing number of astrology apps as social platforms and single card tarot readings as self care, I keep in mind Silvia Federici’s passing remark about the efficacy of the cultural acceptance of magic in the historical present, “astrology too can be allowed to return” as long as we still consult our watches before heading to work. The quip calls into question the disjunction between magic’s appearance and its inhabitation, as practice resistant to enclosure. It also, for me, highlights how there seems to be little consensus on the contemporary fulcrum of protest, refusal, and political change, especially intergenerationally. If the prior two centuries “of Earth” gave us increased industrialization and extractivism, what becomes the new resistant yet affirmative terrain as the former becomes entirely exhausted? Perhaps one theory of political change lies in a transformation of the quality of time: not whether, but which, and whose, watches we consult. This is not a historically new idea to reject or rethink time as an alternative coordination tool, and one that is not principally dependent on material conditions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;20200205_ak.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of the Antikythera mechanism on display at the National Archaeological Museum in Athens, Greece&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An early time machine, the Antikythera mechanism was found by divers off the coast of a Greek island in 1901. The mechanism is dated between 200 B.C. and 87 B.C. and considered by some to be the first analogue computer known so far. Reconstructed from 82 fragments, the mechanism itself consists of 37 gear wheels, which followed the movements of the Sun and Moon throughout the sky, correctly accounting for the Moon’s irregular orbit, and calculated eclipse cycles. Inscriptions on the gear wheels reference the Saros cycle, Metonic spiral, and the zodiac. The mechanism not only measures astronomical time, but its gear system actually utters a complex, mechanical grammar of correspondence to orbiting bodies, already replete with horoscopic narratives. Correspondence was deeply tied to the practice of early astronomy. From the association of emerald gems with Mercury to recognition of planetary hours, astronomical measurement was not separate from but also an aesthetic task, which cultivated incredibly resilient symbols.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, a dominant experience of time is translated from orbiting planetary bodies to corresponding regulation in digital machines, which keep our devices in constant, unprecedented sync; mobile devices are an expression of the medium of time that enforces its serialization. There was a possibility for our devices to derive their initial logic from elsewhere. Rather than skeuomorphic telephones, these portable circuits, liquid, and glass might have become the explicit wayfinding tools of earlier designs for companion devices. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;20200205_gps.png&quot; alt=&quot;Garmin GPS 12XL design from 1998&quot; &#x2F;&gt;	&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of regressing into nostalgia for surveillance prototypes, is it still possible to think through a new logic of companion devices? Their connection rhythmic over only call and response, through alignment of time or its disappearance altogether: the Great De-Sync. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Ever dreamt of an opensource watch U can customize with PYTHON. It would let you create YOUR own communication LORA apps, with on-board MESH, open-source technical specifications &amp;amp; 3D plans if you want mods? Where no-one but you can control the obsolescence.We are making it now! &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.co&#x2F;vr177rVXRB&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com&#x2F;vr177rVXRB&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;&amp;mdash; pwav robot (@pwavrobot) &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;pwavrobot&#x2F;status&#x2F;1218920700582465538?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 19, 2020&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;platform.twitter.com&#x2F;widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A New Time Machines Working Group assuredly wouldn&#x27;t inherit a limited notion of machine correspondence, or embrace it too abstractly either.  Machines have a talent for producing cultural patterns around their use, and practices also have an ability to produce machines. The practice of &lt;em&gt;perpensation horarum&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; is the mental articulation of the passing of the hours, a contemplative act, in which time and life become nearly coincident in their experience. This habit was central to early Franciscan monasteries, which grew into institutional arbiters of time and memory in their own right. Practices themselves—of apocalypse, astrology, and atomic clocks—all produce different and coinciding time machines; those which are eternal, correspondent, and serial.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The New Time Machines Working Group&#x27;s resolve would lie in its ability to navigate varied, novel, and multiple expressions of time as a medium.  Its experimental research themes might include the viability of time independence movements, how to heal disjointed, co-located timelines, or practices that produce machines for non-linear time. The Group would rest, primarily, on the hypothesis that if today&#x27;s time is made by machines, then we may need different machines to remake time. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;BPR.png&quot; alt=&quot;Blogger Peer Review Seal&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Many thanks to the Blogger Peer Review for their thoughts and feedback.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Some true, some farce: Predictions for the 2020s</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>https://ourmachine.net/writing/predictions-2020s/</link>
                <guid>https://ourmachine.net/writing/predictions-2020s/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;eclipse.png&quot; alt=&quot;Depiction of lunar eclipse by Zakariya ibn Muhammad Qazwini (ca. 1203-1283)&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all signs pointing to social platforms as time-sucking maelstroms and phones as anti-dream machines, this year I’ve decided to experiment with posting more of what I actually think about in public. It feels fitting to start this endeavor by contributing to the common pool of predictions for the next decade. Enjoy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A non-exhaustive list:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changes in understanding of genetics and general epistemological shifts in biotech discredit the overarching mainstream narrative of Darwinian evolution.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Panspermia becomes legitimate discourse.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explicitly sacred or blessed objects become the new artisanal consumer object: app subscription magicware.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The dominant trend becomes prepper medievalism; aesthetics can be typified along a single continuum between specific and generic.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two or three AR games rewire 40% of humanity’s social graph.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The distinction between financial and social software applications totally disappears.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Price will be so absolutely identified with objects and information that currency will function as an infrastructural layer more than as an explicit medium of exchange.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New space technology will suddenly exist; odd partnerships arise, e.g. ESA tries to partner on initiatives more often with the CNSA.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are increasingly visible plays for global government alterior to existing institutions; outer space and spectrum become the venue for this negotiation, with incentive alignments like the U.S. and Luxembourg, etc., plus Russia and China.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nations will continue electing genocidal leadership parties. (N.B. with dismantled healthcare systems, descriptors like “right” need to be more direct.)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communities are atomized along climate zones.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are pan-city climate zones. &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A “number” rating emerges that defines average per capita sustenance based on arable land zones; some governments (usually post-colonial) try to enforce this.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Millennials and younger generations that still even see a political arena, see a theory of political change in shifts at an ontological (and often virtual) reality base-layer rather than electoral politics at scale.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still, some believe a new political party is possible.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most mountains stay mountains.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image: Depiction of lunar eclipse by Zakariya ibn Muhammad Qazwini (ca. 1203-1283), Walters Museum Collection&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Byzantine Generalization Problem: Subtle Strategy in the Context of Blockchain Governance</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>https://ourmachine.net/writing/byzantine-generalization-problem/</link>
                <guid>https://ourmachine.net/writing/byzantine-generalization-problem/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One neuroatypical Roman emperor-to-be had a steep onboarding process for his court astrologer. Tiberius Julius Caesar would walk prospective astrologers along the coastline, drawing out their forecasts for pivotal events: a river flooding or a coup on the current emperor. As they wound their way to the highest cliff, he would ask them to look upon their own astrological birth chart and foresee their death, only to be thrown into the rocks below moments later.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t until the astrologer Thrasyllus—who would go on to successfully predict the current emperor’s ousting and the rise of Tiberius—looked up from his own chart to say, “It looks like I’m in grave danger right now,” that he filled the court position.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we look back condescendingly on the centuries when stars acted as movable spokes for power, the credibility we attribute to our own maps of the future may stand on equally influenced ground.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;skin-in-whose-game&quot;&gt;Skin in whose game?&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is my estimate that approximately 2,321 blockchain whitepapers contain the phrase “skin in the game.” Repopularized by Nicholas Nassim Taleb, author of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;The_Black_Swan:_The_Impact_of_the_Highly_Improbable&quot;&gt;The Black Swan&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and the chaos cults’ preemptive answer to Jordan B. Peterson, the phrase signifies the degree of personal risk someone assumes in a given situation. Put your money where your mouth is; make it or break it; or when signifying prediction markets today, vote values but bet beliefs. While the phrase can have many interpretations, it can be one way to divide the opportunists from the invested, those who stand behind the opinions they espouse. In Taleb’s conception, within the bounds of the “game,” those who stand with nothing to lose act for social signaling—positioning themselves loudly while committing nothing. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the story of Tiberius and Thrasyllus, the emperor-to-be put the astrologer’s life at risk, but the question of the astrologer’s agency remains. Did the emperor’s reputation precede him through stories of the other would-be astrologers, or did the Thrasyllus astrologer enter into the risky situation unaware, without other options? As in Thrasyllus&#x27; case, the majority&#x27;s position of a power asymmetry between an individual and their environment, or an individual and an institution, means an individual’s stake is primarily defined externally. The intermediating, or more powerfully leveraged, actor is more capable of setting the terms and risks of engagement.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blockchain technology claims to be trustless, in the sense that individuals don’t have to trust intermediaries or more powerful single actors in order to act and interact. The technical system seeks to off-load authority onto a transparent and public consensus history, created and validated by the protocol and some of its users. The technical system could be considered a “trustless,” multiauthored actor in its own right, with the however unlikely and expensive scenario of its own validators’ collusion. “We don’t need to trust each other before we can begin to collaborate,” blockchain technology claims. Through the massively poor media reporting on blockchain that conflates technically decentralized computation with meaningfully horizontal social organizations, this claim is often misinterpreted, as today’s dominant social connotation of trust suggests something interpersonal and chosen. The term “trustless” skims over that what may have been previously defined as “trust”—as in &lt;em&gt;trusted institutions&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;—and in many scenarios may not refer to voluntary, cultivated relationships but instead arise as a result of contingency and lack of alternatives. In this light, trust was the network effect of rumors around consolidation of power.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter a peer-to-peer, replicated state machine, or by another name, a blockchain. By producing consensus history through cryptography and computational power, asset-backed blockchain applications can allow individuals to define the degree of their own stake, their own investment and risk. They can also rewrite the boundaries of the game, so that those who are unwilling or perhaps unable to evidence stake, “skin in the game,” cannot play at all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;pregrame-theory&quot;&gt;Pregrame theory&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bitcoin whitepaper claimed blockchain to be a general solution for Byzantine fault tolerance in computer science, which takes its name from the game theoretical Byzantine Generals’ Problem.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Byzantine Generals’ Problem has to do with agreement. The illustrative story tells of a group of commanding generals who encircle a city and have to formulate an attack plan. There are two options: attack or retreat, and the generals need to come to a consensus decision in order to make the plan effective. Having surrounded the city and further complicating matters, the generals are geographically distant from one another, so that in order to communicate their decision to each other, they have to rely on a messenger. A messenger who might take the fastest route through the city center to the other side might be efficient, but there would be no way of knowing if their message had been tampered with: Were they bribed at the gate? What if the messenger never arrives?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In computer science, “Byzantine fault tolerance” describes the dependability of a system to reach accurate consensus with potentially unreliable actors. The Bitcoin blockchain addresses this issue by assuming that the computational power required from a malicious actor to attack the network would be too great and too expensive to be able to override the other actors on the network.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;byzantine&#x2F;img2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2 of Swords Tarot card&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;2 of Swords. Tarot card from the Rider-Waite tarot deck. Artist: Pamela Coleman Smith, 1909.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The design of incentives becomes integral to consensus-driven technical systems, which aim to coordinate many actors at scale and navigate a slew of game theoretical problems. Illustrated by the cross-wired motivations in the case of the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Prisoner%27s_dilemma&quot;&gt;Prisoner’s Dilemma&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, coordination and cooperation relies on aligning as much as possible the &amp;quot;best&amp;quot; interest of an individual or organization with the others involved. Incentive design can be read as mechanistically hedging against organizational stalemates or failures.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than seeing technical, incentivized solutions to social problems, we could alternatively read governance issues as archetypal—mutable and immutable, recurring, and taking intractable forms.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;byzantine&#x2F;img3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Lovers Tarot card&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The Lovers. Tarot card from the Rider-Waite tarot deck. Artist: Pamela Coleman Smith, 1909.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These recurring patterns are typically mitigated by governance. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.unescap.org&#x2F;resources&#x2F;what-good-governance&quot;&gt;According to&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the power law editor crowd of Wikipedia, the definition of governance is “the process of decision-making and the process by which decisions are implemented (or not implemented). This definition, however, leaves out a critical first-mover question: How do you make—or more pointedly, who makes—the first decision about the decision-making process without one already in place?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While a paradoxical problem on paper, each day “first decisions” are made at differing scales. Whether it’s &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Antigone&quot;&gt;sweeping gestures&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or incremental everyday actions, the ability to establish a new foundational process for how decisions are made and how action is undertaken structurally determines the course of a society, government, or organization. The &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;The_Tyranny_of_Structurelessness&quot;&gt;tyranny of structurelessness&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;—a poorly lit space filled with vague cultural norms and technical limitations but still anything other than empty—is the space from which explicit governance always emerges and into which it sometimes returns.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;blockchain-incentivizes-time-travel&quot;&gt;Blockchain incentivizes time travel&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the current debate around decentralized platforms, the question, Who is responsible for making the decision on how to make decisions?, comes into focus.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;medium.com&#x2F;@FEhrsam&#x2F;blockchain-governance-programming-our-future-c3bfe30f2d74&quot;&gt;post&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from November 2017, Fred Ehrsam, co-founder of Coinbase, claimed, “Governance is the most vital problem in the [blockchain] space,&amp;quot; stating that the most resilient blockchains will be those that can actively adapt to their environment. He details approaches to on-chain governance, which can be summarized as a blockchain having a decision-making system implemented in code. The various approaches include voting, whereby possessing one cryptotoken will allow you one vote, or having a fully verified identity on your account will allow you one vote, a half-verified identity a half-vote, and so on. He goes on to mention &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;blog.ethereum.org&#x2F;2014&#x2F;08&#x2F;21&#x2F;introduction-futarchy&#x2F;&quot;&gt;futarchy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Fork_(software_development)&quot;&gt;forking&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Voting on-chain could encompass issues such as protocol updates—new features and security fixes—and changes in governance processes and community stakeholders.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;on-chain-governance&quot;&gt;On-chain governance&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 “Person” = 1 Vote &lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Problem: You can create infinite accounts.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
1 Token = 1 Vote&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Problem: You get plutarchy.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
1 Verified Identity = 1 Vote &lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
1 50% Verified Identity = 0.5 Vote&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
 1 Anonymous “Identity” = 0.25 Vote &lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Question: Do we want verified blockchain identities?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two weeks later, Vlad Zamfir countered with &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;medium.com&#x2F;@Vlad_Zamfir&#x2F;against-on-chain-governance-a4ceacd040ca&quot;&gt;Against on-chain governance&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, arguing governance is a complex social process that shouldn’t be fully technically encoded, and perhaps more importantly, that those parachuting into the governance debate to propose solutions with far-reaching impact undermine the development and community work that has come before, potentially disenfranchising actors that are not accounted for in a social or voting-based governance system. Whether it’s Ethereum’s the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;The_DAO_(organization)&quot;&gt;DAO&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or Bitcoin’s &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;SegWit2x&quot;&gt;SegWit2x&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; deliberations and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.bitcoin.it&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;New_York_Agreement&quot;&gt;New York Agreement&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, so far there have been discussions and lengthy deliberations around blockchain governance, on how to counter changes in the protocol and on how to technically travel back in block-time to before a hack, and while processes like the submission of Ethereum Improvement Protocols (EIP) are themselves improving, it&#x27;s suggested that it might be beneficial that more governance standards have yet to be set in stone for developing technology that needs room to iteratively fail and succeed. A core issue with this is, then, if in the meantime someone can come in to effectively make the first decision about how decisions are made, leaving all other choices absurdly empty.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;byzantine&#x2F;img4.png&quot; alt=&quot;The DAO&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-byzantine-generalization-problem&quot;&gt;The Byzantine Generalization Problem&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the arguments around governance abound, the question of what’s at stake in the discussion remains hazy. Depending on who you ask, it’s anything from the future of all asset exchange or organizational design to simply the fates of a small group of developers and a few entangled bystanders arguing over software updates. Either way, “governance” and “game theory” are terms that can be easily deployed to obfuscate a task at hand. In computer security, there’s a concept of “attack surface,” the total possible attack vectors in a technical system—that is, hackable entrance points for data entry and extraction. It’s best practice to keep the attack surface as small as possible. A simple metaphor would be how many doors with faulty locks one house has.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;byzantine&#x2F;img5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Diagram modeling computer security attack surface&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Source: unknown&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is an idea among certain cryptocurrency communities that while in security there is an attack surface, in questions of governance, there is an “argument surface”: the total optionality in a given system or organization. That is, each next step or action that can be enacted in more than one way opens the space for deliberation and argumentation, and therefore they argue perhaps it would be better to limit the argument surface, too, by off-loading as much as one can to a technical system in order to keep acting. For example, in a blockchain context, if the amount of transactions processed in every “block” had to be decided by the community, it would open a vast possibility for argument and contention. Instead, what is referred to as the “block size” is technically predetermined by the protocol. Despite this false conflation of decentralized technical systems and social governance issues, for many operating in this context, the argument for minimizing the amount of actions taken stands as an example of resilient governance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there’s significant overlap between game theoretical problems in computer science and human organization, many distinctions undoubtedly remain. As a governance mechanism, consensus is defined as unanimous agreement, or at least no remaining challenges to an agreement. Matan Field, from &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;daostack.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;DAOstack&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;epicenter.tv&#x2F;episode&#x2F;237&#x2F;&quot;&gt;delineates&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; between “objective consensus,” required by a technical system to be in agreement about the order of previous actions and its current state, and “subjective consensus,” the only semi-explicitly charted terrain, which is the argument surface through which humans deliberate and make decisions. Subjective consensus is rooted in conversation: making an argument for the best way forward and debating any alternatives. Of course these forms of consensus are entangled, but they are not homologous.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;byzantine&#x2F;img6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Tower Tarot card&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The Tower. Tarot card from the Rider-Waite tarot deck. Artist: Pamela Coleman Smith, 1909.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is, however, something like a third way: an inexact science for navigating the Tower as the false consciousness tragedy of the commons, while the assembly meeting goes two hours over schedule. However overstated, the idea of a governance framework’s “argument surface&amp;quot; has an important takeaway, evident in the backlash against Ehrsam’s post calling for urgent action on blockchain governance: the question of who can claim the ability to make first decisions and who can continue to custom frame the governance issues. While perhaps lack of governance has seen the politics of early Bitcoin become stalemated into creating privately distributed ledgers for improving banks’ paperwork, there is a tendency of &lt;em&gt;governance creep&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; in any fledgling organization or stewarded resource, in which the frequency of discussions on governance processes has an odd relationship to the effectiveness of putting said governance in place, perhaps avoiding capture.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;byzantine&#x2F;img7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pseudo-graph by the author demonstrating the BGP&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When all basic decisions start becoming decisions of governance, when all questions are questions of agency to make a decision, a curious epiphenomena occurs. It’s here that totalizing jurisdiction approaches the asymptote of impossibility of action.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;byzantine&#x2F;img8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pseudo-graph by the author demonstrating the BGP&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Byzantine Generalization Problem describes when all issues in an organization or technical system are framed as governance issues. Any question that’s brought before an organization can become a question of who has the agency to provide the solution. Even if it’s fixing the broken plumbing in a housing co-op, when framed as a governance issue, the debate on who should take care of it could last for weeks as the pipes leak and the toilets fail to drain. The generalization of governance can be applied to every challenge an organization faces, especially when there is no clear—or technically embedded—solution at hand. When the complexity of the organization grows, this “generalization problem” applies exponentially, with considerably less clarity on the necessity of action than in the example above.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A DDoS attack on governance, the Byzantine Generalization Problem is the opposite means to the same end of the tyranny of structurelessness. In consensus culture, often the most indefatigable wins, and power is implicitly consolidated by those who provoke interrogations of process. Perhaps a social formula lurks that can be translated fully into equation—amidst curve in the pseudo-chart above—that would lead to transparency, clarity, and appropriate calibration of deliberation on governance systems. Likely not. Everyone has their opinions on how to solve it regardless, ad nauseam and ad infinitum.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That said, as we learn from programs that sponsored the use of consensus, the Byzantine Generalization Problem can be used as a strategy to delay decision-making when necessary and to tactically, obliquely question the right to power. Ambiguous, unattended responsibilities are the “attack surface” and way in.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;byzantine&#x2F;img9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Diagram of Stewart Brand&#x27;s Pace Layering&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Source: Stewart Brand. The Clock of the Long Now: Time and Responsibility, 37. New York: Basic Books, 1999.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another strategy could be to start with a given end goal and seek to map the context and required actions for it to be reached. Such a theory of change relies on an adequate mental model of the environment—with the corollary that the greater the complexity of the environment, the more obfuscated its model’s underlying assumptions are—and importantly, it relies on formulating a multiplicity of understandings of how change may occur in the environment. While governance, incentives, and protocols may be the most explicit frameworks to guide organizational action, there are always other tools available and already at play. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A theory of change can metabolize its environment through time and narrative, incorporating strategies with ulterior rhythms and cloaked intentions. The most efficient path from A to B may be the most hidden and illogical one, based on learning acquired from missteps and faulty data. In the pace-laying diagram above, we can conceive of the different rhythms of change—from the slow yet impactful arc of &amp;quot;culture&amp;quot; and the informative flippancy of fashion—and formulate narrative strategies and technical impositions intersecting with each.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;byzantine&#x2F;img10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Every Ethereum Logo&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Every Ethereum Logo&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aesthetic narratives and false juxtapositions propel change as equally as, if not more than, governance protocols do. Every narrative can be framed in every light. Ethereum, a blockchain platform and protocol that launched in 2015, has seen its own innumerable iterations and adaptations since. Each Ethereum logo has its own part to play—or something. Trusted governance and authenticity must be considered a question not solely of explicit or defined processes but also of subtler forms of manipulation.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has become critical to realize that there has always been fake news, and moreover, that exposing the most accurate information will not in any way necessitate it being acted upon. Fake news—what previous generations may have confined to an understanding of propaganda—is the inevitable result of both massive media industries and small-scale social gossip that travels from one town to the next. Misinformation often comes in gradients, and its propulsion can be as similarly effective as diverse aesthetic and implicit narratives. The Truth is always preceded by a bounty on its name.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each time you point a finger at falsity without offering a significant, desirable counter narrative, politically or aesthetically, you grant the authority of truth-making a wider warrant to dismiss all facts.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is by hyperstitionally navigating ambiguity, taking into account the tools unused and the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.ribbonfarm.com&#x2F;2015&#x2F;05&#x2F;07&#x2F;weaponized-sacredness&#x2F;&quot;&gt;egregores&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; at play, that claims to governance can be made. In the case of blockchain and decentralized governance platforms as they become more widespread, overwhelmingly not all those affected by the outcome of a decision will possess the requisite asset to proportionally offer their stake. If you have the first-decision-maker advantage, how do you shift the terms of who&#x27;s allowed to have skin in the game to be more inclusive of affected parties and to truly cede power?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The debate surrounding decentralized governance assumes governance is the main arena for enacting change, but as in the &amp;quot;self-owning&amp;quot; forest of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;terra0.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;terra0&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the exponentiating legibility of inhuman and ecological actors’ agency to capital will increasingly transform our understanding of what governance decisions have always been made outside of our process-based control. Legibility to capital, however, is not our end goal.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Byzantine Generalization Problem purposefully escapes exact science, it’s perhaps with a more nuanced understanding of how to leverage governance claims that Thrasyllus’s ability to correctly and adaptively read the conditions of power at stake in his own stars may find its home in the direct action of the future.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;divider&quot;&gt;&amp;#9675;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: This essay was originally published in the HKW&#x27;s Technosphere magazine August 2018 dossier on Trust. In the previous version of this essay, I referenced technical governance ideas from a prominent cryptocurrency personality that has since publicly supported and retweeted discrimination and racism. I do not want to provide a referential platform for this person, and I apologize for any harm I have done in legitimizing their work, as well as any lack of accountability I have shown by not previously interrogating their background further. I contacted Technosphere magazine on November 16, 2019 to revise the essay with an appended note; however, the magazine had already been archived and was no longer editable. I republish this revised essay here to commit to learning and doing better.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
