<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>ourmachine.net</title>
        <link>https://ourmachine.net</link>
        <description></description>
        <generator>Zola</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="https://ourmachine.net/tags/ar/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>Some true, some farce: Predictions for the 2020s</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>https://ourmachine.net/writing/predictions-2020s/</link>
                <guid>https://ourmachine.net/writing/predictions-2020s/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;eclipse.png&quot; alt=&quot;Depiction of lunar eclipse by Zakariya ibn Muhammad Qazwini (ca. 1203-1283)&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all signs pointing to social platforms as time-sucking maelstroms and phones as anti-dream machines, this year I’ve decided to experiment with posting more of what I actually think about in public. It feels fitting to start this endeavor by contributing to the common pool of predictions for the next decade. Enjoy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A non-exhaustive list:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changes in understanding of genetics and general epistemological shifts in biotech discredit the overarching mainstream narrative of Darwinian evolution.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Panspermia becomes legitimate discourse.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explicitly sacred or blessed objects become the new artisanal consumer object: app subscription magicware.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The dominant trend becomes prepper medievalism; aesthetics can be typified along a single continuum between specific and generic.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two or three AR games rewire 40% of humanity’s social graph.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The distinction between financial and social software applications totally disappears.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Price will be so absolutely identified with objects and information that currency will function as an infrastructural layer more than as an explicit medium of exchange.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New space technology will suddenly exist; odd partnerships arise, e.g. ESA tries to partner on initiatives more often with the CNSA.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are increasingly visible plays for global government alterior to existing institutions; outer space and spectrum become the venue for this negotiation, with incentive alignments like the U.S. and Luxembourg, etc., plus Russia and China.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nations will continue electing genocidal leadership parties. (N.B. with dismantled healthcare systems, descriptors like “right” need to be more direct.)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communities are atomized along climate zones.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are pan-city climate zones. &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A “number” rating emerges that defines average per capita sustenance based on arable land zones; some governments (usually post-colonial) try to enforce this.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Millennials and younger generations that still even see a political arena, see a theory of political change in shifts at an ontological (and often virtual) reality base-layer rather than electoral politics at scale.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still, some believe a new political party is possible.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most mountains stay mountains.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image: Depiction of lunar eclipse by Zakariya ibn Muhammad Qazwini (ca. 1203-1283), Walters Museum Collection&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
